MDM/PEO0002-0212 1

Privacy Policy

We are IRIS Software Group, whose registered Head office is at: Heathrow Approach. 470

London Road, Slough, SL3 8QY ("We"). We are committed to protecting and respecting your

privacy.

Our primary business is “data processing”.

This means that we process information given to us by other parties. In order to do this, we

enter contracts with organisations (such as schools and clubs) and it is those organisations

(the “Organisation”) that control the personal data and have responsibilities to you as the

data controller. We are also under obligations to ensure your data is processed properly.

When acting as the data ‘Processor’ we are provided with the following personal data by the

‘Organisation’ we are contracted to;

Name

Email address

Mobile number

Address (if present)

Childs name

Childs DOB (For user account validation purposes ONLY)

It is important you have read and understood the Organisation’s privacy policy and please

contact the Organisation for more details about the terms upon which we process data on

their behalf.

Where we directly control your data, for example enquiry forms on Our Website, we set out

details below.

SO WHAT IS THIS DOCUMENT?

This document is called a ‘Privacy statement’ and this tells you how We use personal data

We process. In places this document also clarifies how We treat personal data that We

process on behalf of other Organisations.

Please read this document carefully to understand our views and practices regarding your

personal data and how We will treat it. By visiting https://www.parentmail.co.uk or

https://pmx.parentmail.co.uk and/or by downloading and using the app you are accepting

and consenting to the practices described in this policy.

For the purpose of the Data Protection Act 2018 (and any successor or replacement

legislation) (the Act), the data processor/controller is IRIS Software Group and our

nominated representative under the Act is Our Group Data Protection Officer, Vincenzo

Ardilio.

MDM/PEO0002-0212 2

INFORMATION WE PROCESS ABOUT YOU AS A DATA PROCESSOR

In order to access our software (the Service), users must confirm the following information

to validate their identity (Login Details) and create a ParentMail account:

a. Email address – Account ID

b. Where applicable, child’s DOB for user account for validation purposes only

They must then create a user defined Password in order to access the service.

INFORMATION WE PROCESS ABOUT YOU AS A DATA CONTROLLER

• General information you give us. This is information that you give us by filling in enquiry

forms on our website (our site) or using our support services. The information you give

us may include your name, address, e-mail address and phone number and other

information.

• Information We collect about you. With regard to each of your visits to our site or our

app We will automatically collect the following information:

• Technical Information. Including the Internet protocol (IP) address used to

connect your computer to the Internet, your login information, browser type

and version, time zone setting, browser plug-in types and versions, operating

system and platform;

• Location information. We may also use GPS technology to determine your

current location. Some of our location-enabled services require your personal

data for the feature to work. If you wish to use the particular feature, you will be

asked to consent to your data being used for this purpose. You can withdraw

your consent at any time by disabling location sharing services on your device.

• Information about your visit, including the full Uniform Resource Locators (URL).

WHY DO WE HAVE YOUR DATA?

We provide an engagement platform allowing educational organisations to communicate

with its users. If you use the Service we require Login Details in order to authenticate your

access to the Service.

We also process a range of personal data as part of the Service. This is processed for the

functionality of the Service We are providing, as We are obliged to do so under a contract

with an organisation, and We do so with a legitimate business interest.

All information given is held on our servers located in an ISO27001 accredited data centre.

We are also Cyber Essentials accredited and have in place a stringent security policy covering

all aspects of information management and continuously review and audit our processes.

The following security measures shall be implemented by the Processor, as a minimum:

• Data encryption in transit

• Data encryption at rest

MDM/PEO0002-0212 3

• Role-based access control

• Multi-factor authentication

• Regular backups

• Monthly 3rd party vulnerability scanning

• Intrusion detection system

• Intrusion prevention system

• Firewall protection

• Anti-virus on all IRIS Software Group computers and laptops

• Business continuity plan

HOW LONG DO WE HOLD YOUR DATA FOR?

The information we store from you is held for the following lengths of time:

• ParentMail Account Data – Your data will be held whilst you have a connection to an

organisation.

• In the event that you have no connection, either as a staff user or as a parent, for a

period of 30 days or more, your user data will be automatically deleted. Your User

data will also be removed if you delete your own account.

• General Information You Give Us (as a school user) – Data collected as part of

completion of an enquiry form etc. is held for a maximum period of 24 months and

will only be used for marketing communications where consent, at the time of

submitting the form via the website (Our Site), is provided.

• As a parent, you should be contacting your school for support in the 1st instance. Any

data collected through app store reviews will be held on the respective stores for the

life span of the app

• Payment Schools Application Process – Information collected for the Know Your

Customer (KYC checks) process are retained, as required by HMRC, for a minimum of

7 years.

COOKIES

Our website and app use cookies to distinguish you from other users. This helps us to

provide you with the most effective experience when you browse our website and also

allows us to improve our site. For detailed information on the cookies We use and the

purposes for which We use them see our Cookie Policy at

https://pmx.parentmail.co.uk/resources/terms-and-conditions/cookie-policy.pdf

USES MADE OF THE INFORMATION

We use information held about you in the following ways:

• Information you give to us. We will use this information:

• to carry out our contractual obligations to perform the Service and as part of a

legitimate business purpose;

• to notify you about changes to our service;

• to ensure that content from our site is presented in the most effective manner

MDM/PEO0002-0212 4

for you and for your computer or device.

• Information We collect about your device. We will use this information:

• to administer our site and for internal operations, including troubleshooting,

data analysis, testing, research, statistical and survey purposes;

• to improve our site to ensure that content is presented in the most effective

manner for you and for your computer;

• to allow you to participate in interactive features of our service, when you

choose to do so;

• as part of our efforts to keep our site safe and secure;

• Information We receive from other sources. We will combine this information with

information you give to us and information We collect about you. We will use this

information and the combined information for the purposes set out above (depending

on the types of information We receive).

DISCLOSURE OF YOUR INFORMATION

In order to provide the service to educational organizations and users (such as staff users and

parents) we use the following selected third parties or sub processors. The information

provided is only that is necessary to provide the service.:

▪ AWS SES - Email Sending Service where we provide email address

▪ Reach, AQL - SMS Sending services where we provide mobile number

▪ Barclays and PayPal - Payment processing services where we provide emailaddress and name

▪ PayPoint PayCash - Payment processing service where we provide email address

and name

▪ Gainsight - Used for analytics and engagements to system users

We have data processing agreements in place with all of our providers.

There may be other instances it may be necessary to disclose information. For example:

• In the event that We sell or buy any business or assets, in which case We may disclose

your personal data to the prospective seller or buyer of such business or assets.

• If We or substantially all of our assets are acquired by a third party, in which case

personal data held by it about its customers will be one of the transferred assets.

• If We are under a duty to disclose or share your personal data in order to comply with

any legal obligation, or in order to enforce or apply our terms of use.

WHERE WE STORE YOUR PERSONAL DATA

The data that We collect from you will not be transferred to, and stored at, a destination

outside the European Economic Area ("EEA"). By submitting your personal data, you agree

to this transfer, storing or processing. We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure

that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this privacy policy.

MDM/PEO0002-0212 5

All data stored within the ParentMail systems is stored in an encrypted format using hash

algorithms ensuring that your data is secure.

All information you provide to us is stored on our secure servers. All interactions with the

ParentMail service including payment transactions will be encrypted using SSL technology.

Where We have given you (or where you have chosen) a password which enables you to

access certain parts of our site, you are responsible for keeping this password safe and

confidential. We ask you not to share a password with anyone.

Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure.

Although We will do our best to protect your personal data, We cannot guarantee the

security of your data transmitted to our site; any transmission is at your own risk. Once We

have received your information, We will use strict procedures and security features to try to

prevent unauthorised access.

YOUR RIGHTS

As a school user, you have the right to ask us not to process your personal data for

marketing purposes. We will inform you (before collecting your data) if We intend to use

your data for such purposes or if We intend to disclose your information to any third party

for such purposes. You can exercise your right to prevent such processing by checking

certain boxes on the forms We use to collect your data. You can also exercise the right at any

time by contacting us at dataprotection@iris.co.uk

As a parent user, please contact your school directly for any data subject rights.

Our service may, from time to time, contain links to websites requested by the organisations

we contract with. If you follow a link to any of these websites, please note that these

websites have their own privacy policies and that We do not accept any responsibility or

liability for these policies. Please check these policies before you submit any personal data

to these websites.

ACCESS TO INFORMATION

The Act gives you the right to access information held about you. Your right of access can be

exercised in accordance with the Act.

CHANGES TO OUR PRIVACY POLICY

Any changes We make to our privacy policy in the future will be posted on

https://pmx.parentmail.co.uk/resources/terms-and-conditions/privacy-policy.pdf

Please check back frequently to see any updates or changes to our privacy policy.

CONTACT

Questions, comments and requests regarding this privacy policy are welcomed and should

be addressed to dataprotection@iris.co.uk
